<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Review on Apple Opinions</title><link>/apple-blog/categories/review/</link><description>Recent content in Review on Apple Opinions</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/apple-blog/categories/review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Machineel</title><link>/apple-blog/p/machineel/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/apple-blog/p/machineel/</guid><description>&lt;img src="/apple-blog/p/machineel/machineel.png" alt="Featured image of post Machineel" />&lt;p>The machineel apple is the fruit of the highly poisonous machineel tree. It also goes by the name apple of death.
Every part of the machineel tree is highly toxic for humans. The fluids and sap of the tree cause lasting scars on human skin and eating one of the small fruits would mean a painful death.
Its flavour is described as sweet at first, but with a peppery, stinging aftertaste. Definitely not worth dying for.
You cannot buy the small death apples in stores. But the trees can be found at coastlines in Panama or Florida where there prevent erosion of the soil.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Price: N/A&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rating: deadly/10&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Photo © Hans Hillewaert / CC BY-SA 4.0&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reinata</title><link>/apple-blog/p/reinata/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/apple-blog/p/reinata/</guid><description>&lt;img src="/apple-blog/p/reinata/reinata.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post Reinata" />&lt;p>The Reinata apple is imported from France here in Gran Canaria. It is a tart apple with very little sweetness and a mealy consistency.
The breed is very old and was described as early as 1540 by Frenchman Charles Etienne.
Its name is probably derived from the French word for queen, la reine. The bronze golden color of this apple truly fits its name.
I personally like the taste and consistency. If you have no problem with soft apples, and you like sour fruit, this is a very nice apple.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Price: 2.99€ per kg / 3-4 medium Apples (non organic)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rating: 8/10&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Boskoop</title><link>/apple-blog/p/boskoop/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/apple-blog/p/boskoop/</guid><description>&lt;img src="/apple-blog/p/boskoop/boskoop.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Boskoop" />&lt;p>Boskoop is an older apple breed and it belongs to the winter apples.
That means they are harvested pretty late in the year.
The easiest time to find them in stores are winter months like november or december.
They also are a popular option for baked apples which may be related to this time of year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I would describe the taste of this apple breed as very aromatic and pleasently sour.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you have ever tasted a boskoop you may be surprised to learn that it has a rather high sugar content (according to scientific analysis around 15%)).
This makes Boskoop one of the most sugary apples, at the lower end of the scale are apples with around 11% sugar.
But why does it taste like it does? Because it also has an extraordanary acid content, around 11%&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is a lot going on in this apple.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Boskoops are usually pretty big, and they are also heavy. A normal boskoop weighs around 200g but I regularily see big ones weighing 300 or 400g.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I really like Boskoop, it is my favorite winter time snack and perfect in apple pie.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Price: 2.99€ per kg / ca. 3 big Apples (non organic)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rating: 8/10&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fräulein</title><link>/apple-blog/p/fraulein/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/apple-blog/p/fraulein/</guid><description>&lt;img src="/apple-blog/p/fraulein/fraulein.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Fräulein" />&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Fräulein&amp;rdquo; (German for Miss or little lady) is a apple breed I discovered in my grocery store recently.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Its packaging touts a happy accident crossbreed and the apple itself looks a lot like my all time favorite, Boskoop. The apples I bought had no discernable smell but they had the matt colour and big calibre I associate with a delicious old apple breed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The taste was a bit underwhelming for me. It was sweet and sour and crisp, but it did not have the apple aroma of a Boskoop. The taste reminds me of a nice Elstar. All in all, a solid apple. If you love crisp, not too sweet apples, this apple may be for you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Price: 2.99€ per kg / 4 big Apples (non organic)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rating: 7/10&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Jonagored</title><link>/apple-blog/p/jonagored/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/apple-blog/p/jonagored/</guid><description>&lt;img src="/apple-blog/p/jonagored/jonagored.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post Jonagored" />&lt;p>Jonagored is a medium sized apple with a sweet taste. It is not very sour.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The one I got at the grocery store is a bit watery. But if you put it in the fridge during sommer time it&amp;rsquo;s very refreshing.
I was surprised to learn that Jonagored was discovered very recently in 1986, which makes it a newer apple breed.
The apple is a variant of the Jonagold apple with a more reddish color, therefore the name. Its harvested in summer and available through autumn and winter in Germany.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Price: 2.99€ per kg / 6 medium Apples (non organic)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rating: 6/10&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>