<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>7/10 on Apple Opinions</title><link>/apple-blog/tags/7/10/</link><description>Recent content in 7/10 on Apple Opinions</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/apple-blog/tags/7/10/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fräulein</title><link>/apple-blog/p/fraulein/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/apple-blog/p/fraulein/</guid><description>&lt;img src="/apple-blog/p/fraulein/fraulein.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Fräulein" />&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Fräulein&amp;rdquo; (German for Miss or little lady) is a apple breed I discovered in my grocery store recently.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Its packaging touts a happy accident crossbreed and the apple itself looks a lot like my all time favorite, Boskoop. The apples I bought had no discernable smell but they had the matt colour and big calibre I associate with a delicious old apple breed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The taste was a bit underwhelming for me. It was sweet and sour and crisp, but it did not have the apple aroma of a Boskoop. The taste reminds me of a nice Elstar. All in all, a solid apple. If you love crisp, not too sweet apples, this apple may be for you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Price: 2.99€ per kg / 4 big Apples (non organic)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rating: 7/10&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Jonagored</title><link>/apple-blog/p/jonagored/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/apple-blog/p/jonagored/</guid><description>&lt;img src="/apple-blog/p/jonagored/jonagored.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post Jonagored" />&lt;p>Jonagored is a medium sized apple with a sweet taste. It is not very sour.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The one I got at the grocery store is a bit watery. But if you put it in the fridge during sommer time it&amp;rsquo;s very refreshing.
I was surprised to learn that Jonagored was discovered very recently in 1986, which makes it a newer apple breed.
The apple is a variant of the Jonagold apple with a more reddish color, therefore the name. Its harvested in summer and available through autumn and winter in Germany.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Price: 2.99€ per kg / 6 medium Apples (non organic)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rating: 6/10&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>