<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>8/10 on Apple Opinions</title><link>/apple-blog/tags/8/10/</link><description>Recent content in 8/10 on Apple Opinions</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/apple-blog/tags/8/10/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Reinata</title><link>/apple-blog/p/reinata/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/apple-blog/p/reinata/</guid><description>&lt;img src="/apple-blog/p/reinata/reinata.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post Reinata" />&lt;p>The Reinata apple is imported from France here in Gran Canaria. It is a tart apple with very little sweetness and a mealy consistency.
The breed is very old and was described as early as 1540 by Frenchman Charles Etienne.
Its name is probably derived from the French word for queen, la reine. The bronze golden color of this apple truly fits its name.
I personally like the taste and consistency. If you have no problem with soft apples, and you like sour fruit, this is a very nice apple.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Price: 2.99€ per kg / 3-4 medium Apples (non organic)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rating: 8/10&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Boskoop</title><link>/apple-blog/p/boskoop/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/apple-blog/p/boskoop/</guid><description>&lt;img src="/apple-blog/p/boskoop/boskoop.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Boskoop" />&lt;p>Boskoop is an older apple breed and it belongs to the winter apples.
That means they are harvested pretty late in the year.
The easiest time to find them in stores are winter months like november or december.
They also are a popular option for baked apples which may be related to this time of year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I would describe the taste of this apple breed as very aromatic and pleasently sour.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you have ever tasted a boskoop you may be surprised to learn that it has a rather high sugar content (according to scientific analysis around 15%)).
This makes Boskoop one of the most sugary apples, at the lower end of the scale are apples with around 11% sugar.
But why does it taste like it does? Because it also has an extraordanary acid content, around 11%&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is a lot going on in this apple.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Boskoops are usually pretty big, and they are also heavy. A normal boskoop weighs around 200g but I regularily see big ones weighing 300 or 400g.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I really like Boskoop, it is my favorite winter time snack and perfect in apple pie.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Price: 2.99€ per kg / ca. 3 big Apples (non organic)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rating: 8/10&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>